1944年中期
By the middle of 1944
盟军投入1000架轰炸机
Allied forces were regularly flying raids of 1,000 bombers over Nazi Germany,
在P51野马等远航程战斗机护航下对纳粹德国定期轰炸
Escorted by powerful, long range sightings like the P51 Mustang
德国空军无力抵抗这庞大的空中舰队
the German Luftwaffe could put up little resistance to these vast air armadas
但是在1944年7月
But in July 1944
一种新式德国战斗机出现在天空中
a new German fighter appeared in the skies,
其飞行时速比野马高出100多英里(>160km/h)
capable of flying over one hundred miles per hour faster than the Mustang,
并且装备了4门30mm口径的机炮(Mk-108)
and armed with four thirty millimeter cannons.
可以摆脱护航战斗机而且只用一轮攻击就能摧毁轰炸机
It could outmaneuver the escorts and destroy a bomber in a single pass.
德军的新战机
The new German fighter,
这种让盟军飞行员恐惧，并且让德国空军认为自己不可战胜的
which put fear into the allied pilots and made the German Luftwaffe feeling invincible.
正是喷气式的梅塞施密特262
Was the jet propelled Messerschmitt 262
我第一次看见德国的喷气机Me262时，
The first time I saw a German jet, the Me262
我简直不敢相信 它跑的这么快
I could hardly believe it how faaaaaaaast it was.
这次我们不再是猎物，而是猎人
At this time we were again not the hunted,but the hunters.
所以我们现在有信心取胜
So now we won with a ego.
使用出色的影像档案和重新上色技术，
Using extraordinary archive film and color re-enactments,
《Battle Stations》节目将会深入速度之争，
探索航空史上第一种投入实战的喷气战斗机
Battle stations dives into the high speed world of the race to get the first jet fighter ever to fly in combat.
梅塞施密特262 : 喷气竞赛
Messerschmitt 262：RACE FOR THE JET
讽刺的是，令盟军恐惧的Me262的起源是一张和平条约
Ironically, the origins of the fearsome Messerschmitt 262 were born out of a peace treaty.
在一战战败后
Following its defeat in World War One,
德国被同盟国强制签署禁止发展常规飞行技术的协定，
Germany was forced by the allies to sign an agreement which banned them from developing further conventional aircraft technologies,
然而其中并未提及火箭和喷气推进技术。
that rockets and jet propulsion would never mentioned.
1930年，
in the 1930s
元首开始描绘纳粹德国的蓝图
Adolf Hitler began to build his vision for Nazi Germany.
其中包括世界最强的空军
That vision included the most powerful air force in the world.
为达到这一目标，空军必须有高航速
To achieve this, the airforce must have speed.
当时，
At that time,
人们认识到，飞得更快意味着需要飞的更高
It was realized that to fly faster meant flying higher,
因为高处空气更稀薄(阻力小)
where the air is thinner.
但当飞行高度增加，
but the higher a plane flies,
螺旋桨就更难牵引飞机前进
the harder it is for a propeller to draw it through the air.
在德国哥廷根大学，一位年轻的工程师 汉斯·冯·奥海恩开始了涡轮喷气引擎的研究
At the German University of Göttingen a young engineer named Hans von Ohain began development work on a turbo jet engine.
汉斯·冯·奥海恩是个十分优秀的学生，
他第一次完成喷气引擎的构想时仅有21岁
A brilliant student Hans von Ohain was only twenty one years old when he first conceived the idea of a jet engine.
他是个好学的技术人员
He was a technician with an inquisitive mind.
他非常擅长解决理论问题
He was very good at theoretical problems,
而且他也在学习物理
and he studied physics as well.
受到他教授的鼓舞，
Encouraged by his professor,
这位年轻工程师开始着手制造引擎原型
the young engineer began to build a working prototype.
此时的英国，
Meanwhile, in Britain,
全然不知德国发生的事，26岁的皇家空军飞行员弗兰克·惠特尔
totally unaware of what was happening in Germany,a 26 year old Royal Air Force pilots named Frank Whittle,
正在研发一种燃气涡轮引擎
was developing a gas turbine engine.
1932年
in 1932
他提交了世界上第一份喷气引擎的专利
He filed a patent on the world's first jet engine.
在这个早期片段中
In this early film,
弗兰克·惠特尔亲自解释了引擎的原理
Frank Whittle himself explains the principles of his engine.
这代表一个离心压缩机
This represents a centrifugal type compressor.
用这个在前端吸入空气，像这样压缩进入燃烧室
I use this to pull in air at the front and to compress it into combustion chambers like this,
这里会注入燃料并燃烧，使空气膨胀，
让它有足够的能量驱动压缩机的涡轮
where the injection of burning the fuel * and expand the air and gives it enough energy to drive a turbine which drives the compressor.
这个设计将会成为世界上第一个完全可行的喷气引擎
This design was to become the world's first fully working jet engine.
但惠特尔发现很难让英国军方重视他的设计
But Whittle found it difficult to get his design taken seriously by the British military establishment.
当时科学家，即当权者的建议是这个设计不可行
The scientific advice at that time and i.e by the people in power was it couldn't work.
让它正常工作需要过多的能量
It required just too much power to make it work.
军方人员听取了这个建议
And the officials at the ministry listened to that advice,
惠特尔被视作凭借无稽之谈，妄图使自己一举成名的人
and Whittle was very much seen as a bit of an upstart that was trying to sort of make his name and push forward an idea that was not really achievable at that time.
对惠特尔的阻碍导致的延期，之后将成为德国喷气引擎研究的显著优势
The delays, which were to hamper Whittle were to prove a distinct advantage for German jet engine development.
1935年
By 1935
奥海恩在导师建议下，通过飞机制造商亨克尔的经济支持完成了测试引擎
Hans von Ohain had developed a test engine on the advice of his professor approach the aircraft manufacturer Ernst Hanckel for financial support.
亨克尔作为激进理念的赞助者而出名
Hanckel was known as a patron of radical concepts,
他特别看重那些能提高速度，让他能建造世界最快飞机的技术
especially those which would lead to higher speeds and enable him to build the fastest airplane in the world.
亨克尔对此印象深刻
他意识到这种引擎的巨大潜力，要求制造全尺寸型号
Impressed, Heinkel recognize the enormous potential of such an engine and ordered the construction of a fullscale *power plant.
汉斯和他的工程师团队接受了任务，
开始研发亨克尔HeS 3引擎
Ohain and his team of engineers accepted the task and set to work on what would become the HES 3 jet engine.
回到英国，
Back in Britain,
惠特尔终于筹到了开一间小公司的钱
Whittle had finally managed to raise enough funds to establish a small company.
公司建立在莱斯特郡的拉特沃思小镇
Located in the little Leicestershire town of Lutterworth,
他将其命名为Power Jets
he called it powered jets.
1937年
In 1937,
他第一次测试引擎
he tested his engine for the first time.
惠特尔遇到了各种问题
引擎在匹配时失控，推力逐渐上升
Whittle had all sorts of problems when the engine on *pairing up ran away with itself and just kept going and going the thrust built up,
惠特尔就站在那看着机器爆炸，因为他已经被吓呆了
and Whittle just stood there and waited for it to go bang because he was just transfixed by it.
但同时他也被这个情景所吸引
He also was enthralled by what was happening.
这台机器是他的孩子
This was his baby,
惠特尔不想看着它破裂
and he didn't want it to break fall apart.
他正在悉心照顾这台机器
He was looking after it.
即便其他所有人都明智地立马跑路了
Although everyone else sensibly left the area very quickly.
尽管有许多挫折与失败
Despite many setbacks and failures,
惠特尼最终掌控了他的引擎
which will finally succeeded in controlling his engine.
但是英国政府仍未被说服
but the British government was still not convinced,
政府更倾向传统的飞机和引擎设计
preferring instead conventional designs for aircraft and engines.
惠特尔的发明在整个30年代面临重重阻力
Whittle face resistance to his invention throughout the 1930s.
先前的喷气推进测试表明涡桨飞机将会很重，
Previous experiments with jet propulsion indicated that turboprops will be heavy,
昂贵且不可靠
expensive and very unreliable.
英国航空部和皇家空军认为
The British Air Ministry and the Royal aircraft establishment saw,
喷气推进要想成为飞机动力的可行替代方案，
至少还有10至15年的路要走
that turbo jets were not going to be a viable alternative for Aero propulsion until ten or fifteen years down the road.
与此同时
Throughout this time,
惠特尔并不知道德国人也在研发喷气引擎
Frank Whittle did not know that the Germans were developing a jet engine.
项目的保密非常完善
So good was the secrecy surrounding the project.
研发内容从不为人所知
Little was known about what was being developed at all
当时，惠特尔35年的专利被发布在德国的技术杂志上
Whittle's patents, which were released in 35 and were published in Germany in German in the technical magazines at that time,
奥海恩得知了这一切
made available to von Ohain,
惠特尔已经注册了很多专利
a lot of material Whittle it previously had as a patent,
可以这么说，汉斯已经在阅读这些内容
and now I think it would be fair to say at that time that von Ohain would have gone down the road of reading these,
他不会原样照搬，
he wouldn't have copied it,
但他一定会阅读并且运用到他自己的领域中
but he would certainly have read it and interpreted it into the zones he was involved in.
当战争阴云开始笼罩
As the clouds of war gathered on the horizon,
纳粹政权对开发高速的推进技术更为执着
the Nazi regime had become more determined than ever to develop faster forms of propulsion for its *lift off.
1938年
in 1938,
帝国航空部签发了德国航空工业规范
the Reich Air Ministry issued a specification to the German aviation industry.
一种单座喷气战斗机
A single seat turbo jet fighter.
被这道命令所推动
Spurred on by this directive,
亨克尔的团队推行这项计划
Heinkel's team pushed ahead,
设计一型装备奥海恩引擎的战机
designing an aircraft to be powered by Ohain's jet engines.
得益于绘图板上的两兄弟
From the drawing boards of twin brothers, Siegfried and Walter Gunter,
第一款实用型喷气动力飞机即将起飞
the first practical jet powered aircraft was to take flight.
命名为He-178
It was called the He-178.
1939年8月27日
On August the 27th 1939
在二战爆发前一周
one week before the outbreak of World War II,
小巧的He-178升空
the little Heinkel 178 took to the air.
德国人在喷气引擎竞赛中先行一步
The Germans had succeeded in being first in getting a jet air war.
但制造第一架喷气战斗机的竞赛才刚刚开始
But the race for the first jet fighter had only just begun.
1939年9月3日
On September the 3rd 1939,
二战开始
the Second World War began,
在接下来的几周时间里
and over the next few weeks,
德国人扫清了他们面前的一切
Germany swept all before them.
亨克尔和汉斯对喷气飞机的世界首飞兴奋不已，
Flushed with the success of having just flown the world's first jet aircraft,
两个月后，他们可以向纳粹政府展示飞机了
It was two months before Ernst Heinkel and Hans von Ohain were able to demonstrate their plane to the Nazi government.
但随着纳粹军队所向披靡，传统空军主宰天空
But with its army conquering all and with its conventional airforce becoming masters of the skies,
德国人突然对喷气动力失去了兴趣
the Germans had suddenly lost interest in jet power.
He-178短暂而荣耀的一生结束，余生注定在柏林博物馆度过
The He-178 short but glorious life was over and was destined to spend the rest of his days in a Berlin museum.
但有坚定信念的人仍在默默地完善他自己的喷气飞机设计
But there were others in Germany who did not believe that the race for the first jet fighter was over quietly working on his own jet aircraft design.
这就是后来的Me-262
that would become the Me-262
设计者是杰出的41岁航空工程师：威利·梅塞施密特
was a brilliant 41 year old aeronautical engineer called Wilhelm Messerschmitt.
整个三十年代，梅塞施密特都是战斗机和轰炸机设计者和制造商
Throughout the thirties Messerschmitt had been a designer and manufacturer of bombers and fighters,
这正是纳粹高层所喜欢的项目
a favorite with the Nazi hierarchy,
他是个工作狂，让所有共事的人都忠于他
人们常说他很有艺术才能
he was a workaholic and created loyalty from all that knew him. *It was often he was very artistic.
周末在家时
At home over the course of a weekend,
他会在一张A4纸上设计飞机部件
he could design an aircraft part on an a4 sheet of paper,
图纸马上就能投入生产
and then the drawing would be ready to be taken into the workshop right away.
他可以完成非常好的设计，而且有着敏锐的直觉
His designs were that good. He was a very intuitive person,
但他有时也会大发雷霆
but he would lose his temper a lot.
然而这时，德国当局对喷气工业不再感兴趣
Yet whilst the German authorities appeared to have lost interest in their jet industry.
在英国，惠特尔终于时来运转
In Britain,Frank Whittles fortunes have changed.
在一系列冗长而沮丧的斗争后
After a long and frustrating battle,
英国航空部终于同意投资，并且建造一座工厂用于量产他的喷气引擎
The British Air Ministry finally agreed to finance and build a factory for him to manufacture his jet engine.
验证惠特尔引擎的飞机订单给了格洛斯特航空公司
The Gloucester Aircraft Company was given the contract to produce an experimental plane that would prove Whittle's engines.
验证机名称为E.28
It was called the E.28.
最终在1941年5月15日
Finally on May the 15th 1941
在奥海恩的He-178首飞20个月后，
20 months after Hans von Ohain He-178 had first flown,
格洛斯特E.28终于升空
The Gloucester E.28 took to the air.
首飞对于E.28来说意义重大，
The first flight to the E.28 was a significant event,
显然这是飞机可行性的最终验证
because obviously this was the final proof of the aircraft's operational use.
惠特尔一举成名
Whittle overnight became the success.
之前普遍认为没有螺旋桨的飞机是无法飞行的，
但是他做到了。人们纷纷向他祝贺
He had achieved something that previously people thought wouldn't happen an aircraft flying with no propeller and they were suddenly having him congratulations well done Frank,
然后惠特尔转身解释说：这设计简直太TM适合飞行了
You know, and Frank were to turn around said well it was bloody well designed to fly.
人们十分振奋，其中包括美国陆军参谋长亨利·哈里·阿诺德
Amongst all this excitement was visiting American Army Chief of Staff General Henry Harley Arnold.
他确信这个英国发明可以为美国喷气技术带来很大帮助
He was convinced that this British invention could help to spring board America into the race for the jet.
对英国喷气机的飞行感到非常震惊之余
It was very surprised about the fact that the British had a jet engine aircraft flying,
他只能推测德国人的喷气机研发至少也是这个水准
and he can only speculate that the Germans were at least as far in their development of a jet aircraft as well.
怀着对新型喷气技术的热情和让美国海军赶上新技术的决心，
So, enthusiastic about the new jet technology and wanting to emphasize the U. S Navy catch up,
阿诺德和英国政府协商，将一个惠特尔引擎的样品带回美国
Arnold negotiated with the British government to bring an example of Whittle's engine to the United States,
这样，美国的喷气机项目就能起步了。
So the American turbojet program could begin.
大英首相丘吉尔也很希望美国对于参战的承诺，
因此同意移交惠特尔的喷气引擎
Britain's Prime Minister Winston Churchill was also eager to get the U. S committed to the British war effort and agreed to hand over whittle's jet designs.
丘吉尔的态度是：我们怎么才能把美国拖下水
Churchill's attitude was how can we involve America in our fight against the dictatorships.
他认为通过赠送最新技术给美国，
可以让美国在之后转向支持英国
And he's seen the the fact that we would give this very latest development of technology to the Americans freely would help them appreciate this sort of problems we were in and later on maybe come down on our side.
惠特尔引擎的部件被迅速安排装箱
Hastily arrangements were made to box up Whittle’s engine parts and plans.
作为顶级机密，这箱宝贵的货物被轰炸机送往华盛顿的波音机场
Amidst top secrecy, this precious cargo was loaded into a bomber and flown to a Boeing field In Washington, DC.
之后，引擎被送往位于麻省的通用电气公司工厂
It was then transported to the General Electric plants in Massachusetts.
不同于惠特尔的小规模研发
Unlike the small scale of development that Whittle facing in Great Britain,
美国人致力于调整和改进他的引擎
the American effort in modifying and improving his engine,
用大尺寸进行研制
United States was on a large scale.
在通用的工厂里
At the General Electric plant,
得益于在耐热高强度合金的丰富经验，通用改进了引擎，
最终成果就是GE I-A引擎
the company used its experience in heat-resistant in a high-strength alloys to modify and improve what would eventually become the general electric I-A engines.
我认为这项工作的机密性和重要性再怎么强调也不为过
I cannot overemphasize the secrecy and the importance of this work.
大家都知道意呆利和德国人都在研发喷气技术
We know that both the Italians and the Germans are working on jets.
你们应该都知道一定不能让他们抢占先机
I hardly need to tell you that they must not win the race.
通过授予最高优先权
Given unlimited priority,
我们要在6个月内完成第一台机器
we will have the first unit running on task in six months.
与此同时在德国
Meanwhile, in Germany,
尽管纳粹政府对喷气技术漠不关心
Despite Nazi indifference to the jet,
亨克尔的团队还是在研发喷气战斗机
Heinkel's team continued to develop a jet fighter.
1941年3月30日
On March the 30th 1941,
亨克尔280第一次试飞
the Heinkel 280, had its first test flight.
奥海恩洋洋得意地陶醉在这历史性的场景中
Triumphantly, Hans von Ohain was amongst those who reveled in this momentous occasion.
由他设计的引擎驱动，
Powered by his jet engine,
试验机设计极佳，速度可以超过每小时500英里
the plane was a superb design capable of speeds in excess of five hundred miles per hour.
领先所有竞争对手一大截
It was light years ahead of all its competitors.
这次测试飞行对亨克尔和汉斯都是巨大的个人成就
The test flight was a huge personal success for Heinkel and von Ohain
遗憾的是，他们的飞机注定无法成为赢家
but sadly their jet fighter was not destined to be a winner.
亨克尔的核心问题是没有符合帝国空军部的要求，
因此无法获取合同（无法找到匹配且可靠的引擎 [译者注]）
At the core of Heinkel's problem with getting contracts for operational jet and rocket aircraft was his inability to play by the rules of the Reich Air Ministry.
另一方面，梅塞施密特完全合规，因此获得大量合同
but on the other hand, Messerschmitt was able to play by the rules and was awarded with substantial contracts.
当1941年接近尾声时，
As 1941 drew to a close ,
英美德都加入了喷气研究
Britain America and Germany were all committed to jet development.
但对于美国来说 ，另一个事件让这个竞赛更为激烈
But for America another event made the race more intense.
1941年12月7日,
on December the 7th 1941,
日本偷袭珍珠港
Japan attacked Pearl Harbor.
美国参战给对抗德国的盟军带来了急需的生命线
America's entry into World War II brought a much-needed lifeline to the allies in the battle against Germany.
全面的喷气机竞赛开始了
The full-blown race for the first jet fighter was now on.
英国政府终于批准惠特尔为战斗机研究喷气引擎
In Britain, the government had finally given the go ahead for Frank to develop a jet engine for a fighter.
美国通用公司恢复了所有暂停的研究
In America, General Electric was pulling out all the stops.
他们在6个月内生产引擎的计划进展顺利
Their promise to produce an engine within six months was on target.
同时在德国
And in Germany,
元首认为Me262是优秀的武器，要求梅塞施密特提前投入量产
Hitler now saw the Me-262 as a wonder weapon and pushed Messerschmitt for an early completion to get the plane into production.
他们要我们继续研发，并批准梅塞施密特的一切提案
Do you wonder they wanted us to get a move on and granted permission to any of Messerschmitt's proposals.
德国喷气机工业正全速前进
The German jet aircraft industry was now moving forward at full speed.
研发和创新遍及各处
Research and innovation was everywhere.
设计师和工程师提出的概念超前好几年
Designers and engineers came up with concepts that were years in advance of their time.
机身后掠翼风洞试验让德国飞机制造商领先盟军
Wind tunnel tests into swept wings and fuselage configurations enable the German plane makers to be way ahead of the allies.
我们参考估测以及计算、对比得出的结果，
直到有了那种感觉：
It was a mixture of calculations and calculate this and that and comparisons and was carrying out tells us until you got the feelings,
就是这个！
this was it,
然后他重构、测试、度量，乐在其中
And then he rebuilt it and tried it and measured it, and it was fun.
1942年7月18日
on July the 18th 1942,
这是属于Me-262的一天
the Me-262 made its day.
首飞并不是一帆风顺
At the first flight of the day was not without its *purpose.
我们陷入了困境：机尾无法抬升
We ran into difficulties when the plane's tail would not lift up,
因此我们测试发现，如果飞行员在高速时轻踩刹车
So we ran tests and discovered that if the pilot brakes gently at speed,
机尾就可以抬升了
then the tail would lift up.
措施有效。当飞机时速达到120英里(193km/h)时
It worked. when the aircraft reached 120 miles per hour.
当飞行员轻触刹车，机头下降
The pilots touched the brakes, the nose dropped,
机尾抬升
the tale came up
Me-262成功升空
and the Me-262, took to the air.
Me-262在首飞测试中展示的性能相当惊人
The performance of the Me-262 with its test flight was incredible.
第二次飞行时，爬升到了11500英尺(3505米)，
时速可达450英里(724km/h)
On its second fly to climb to 11,500 feet and
reached the speed of 450 miles per hour.
其他盟军飞机做得到吗？
already, it was faster than any allied planes in existence.
很快，德国飞行员就能在别人只能梦想的时速下飞行
Soon, German pilots would be flying at speeds that others could only have dreamt up.
但Me-262会成为元首的梦想战机吗？
But would the Me-262 be the answer to Hitler's dreams?
现在Me-262的喷气引擎可以让它的时速超过550英里(885km/h)
The Me-262's jet engines could now thrust it at speeds of over 550 miles  per hour.
可以轻易超过一切对手
It could simply outfly anything in the sky.
配备4门30mm口径机炮
Armed with four thirty millimeter cannons,
每一门都可以发射超过80发高爆弹
each was capable of delivering over eighty explosive shells into the enemy.
未来计划包括翼下挂载24发空对空火箭弹
Future plans were also to include 24 wings slung air to air rockets.
代号“燕子”
Nicknamed the Swallow,
这一杰作预示着空战新纪元的黎明
This awesome machine heralded the dawning of a new age of battle.
对纳粹空军来说，它被寄予厚望
And for Hitler's Luftwaffe ,it was hoped that when it finally met the allied forces, it's hell would be unleashed.
这次成功的测试飞行最终说服了空军的将军们
The successful test flight of the German Me-262 had at last proved to the Luftwaffe generals.
这就是可以赢得战争的机器
This was the fighting machine that could win the war,
但在成为满足纳粹目标的无敌机器之前，仍有很多研发工作要做
but a lot of development work was still needed before it could become the all-conquering answer to Nazi dreams.
在美国，两位科学家夜以继日地工作。
In America, two scientists were working around the clock.
通用电气公司已经成功完成喷气引擎的试验
Gec had successfully completed trials with their jet engines.
贝尔航空公司签订了一架实验机合同
The Bell Aircraft Corporation was contracted to supply an experimental plane to test.
1942年10月1日，在绝密护送下
On October the 1st 1942 amidst great secrecy,
美国第一架喷气实验机 XP-59a
America's first jet aircraft called the XP-59a,
在加利福尼亚莫洛克干湖起飞
was flown at Muroc Dry lake in California.
测试结果却令人失望
But the tests were disappointed.
飞机只能达到390英里(627km/h)的最大时速
The aircraft could only manage a maximum speed of 390 miles per hour.
这一速度比很多德国和盟军的活塞动力飞机还慢
This speed was below many of the German and allied piston powered planes.
但是XP-59a仍然是美国未来喷气机工业的重要基础
But the XP-59a, did play an important part in the race and was to be the foundation of America's future jet aircraft industry.
美国喷气研发进程缓慢，
因为美国军方的普遍观点是用现有的武器赢得战争
The American Turbojet Development program proceeded a slow pace because the overall objective of the American military was to win the war with the weapons at hand.
大批量传统活塞引擎飞机的生产，
The construction in large numbers of conventional piston engined aircraft,
例如北美航空公司的P-51野马和波音的B-17
such as the North American P-51 Mustang and the Boeing B-17.
这些看起来才是能赢得战争的武器
Those were seen as the weapons it would win the war,
因此审视喷气技术，这被看做是一项长期工程
So, looking at jet technology, it was seen as a long term development.
然而在德国，Me-262在紧张的评估过程中被提升到最高优先级
Yet in Germany, the Me-262 was given top priority as it went through a period of intense evaluation.
1943年五月
In May 1943,
帝国空军最著名的飞行员加兰德第一次驾驶Me-262
the Luftwaffe's most famous areas Adolf Galland flew the Me-262 for the first time.
驾驶过后，他说：这不是一小步，而是一个飞跃
After the flight, he was a main saying This is not a step forward. This is a leap.
他描述这次的飞行为：“像被天使推动一样”
He also described the flight as like being pushed by angels.
元首也对飞机的性能愈发激动
Hitler too was becoming more and more excited about the plane's performance.
面对即将到来的盟军轰炸机的日常攻击
with his right now coming under daily attacks from allied bombers,
他下令全力投产Me-262
he ordered the Me-262 to be put into full scale production,
不仅作为战斗机，还要有轰炸机的型号
not only as a fighter, but also was a bomber.
元首认为只要有一千架喷气轰炸机
He felt that if he had one thousand jet bombers,
纳粹就可以阻止，至少也能延缓盟军的攻势
they could halt or at least delay the expected Allied invasion.
梅塞施密特被元首问到是否可以在Me-262上装炸弹
Messerschmitt had been asked if you could drop bombs with it.
梅塞施密特回答到：当然可以用它来投弹
Of course you could drop bombs on it.
但这不是最初的设计目的
But that was not what it had been built for .
我们被要求安装炸弹，可是它在翼下仅能挂载两枚
And two bombs were only fitted underneath because we'd been ordered to do so.
部分意见被元首采纳，其他则完全不予理会
Some blame take for it and others tried to put the blame elsewhere.
简直是胡扯
It was all nonsense
战斗机还是轰炸机的纠结将会是灾难性的错误
The confusion and trying to build freighter versions and modify the plan to be a bomber would be a disastrous mistake.
1944年6月6日，盟军成功在诺曼底登陆
On June the 6th 1944 the Allies successfully landed on the beaches of France.
欧洲攻势开始
The invasion of Europe had begun.
德国人想赶走盟军，结果只是徒劳
Vainly the Germans tried to throw the invaders back,
随着盟军夺取取制空权，而没有可用的Me-262
but with the allies having complete air superiority and with no operational Me-262 is available,
德国人被迫撤退
The Germans were forced to retreat.
听到这个消息，元首勃然大怒
On hearing this, it is reported that Hitler flew into a rage.
诺曼底登陆两天后，
And two days after D-day, he announced a *fury befell and order of the leader,
元首下令Me-262只能生产轰炸机型
which demanded the Me-262 be made only as a bomber.
尽管有元首的命令
Despite Hitler's orders,
小批量的战斗机版本还是被生产出来
limited numbers of the fighter version did come off the production line.
这些飞机被火速送往飞行训练学校
They were quickly rushed to the training schools.
这是注定只有精英才能驾驭的机型
Destined to be flown by the elite.
在这里，德国空军的精英第一次看到了Me-262
It was here that the cream of the German Luftwaffe and saw the Me-262 for the first time.
我们第一次看到飞机的时候都震惊了
We were surprised when we first saw it standing there.
机炮简直不可思议
The guns were incredible,
训练这些飞行员成了最优先事项
the training of these pilots was given top priority,
但随着战争潮水涌来
But with the tide of war running against them,
已经没有时间进行战术教学了
there was little time for classroom tactics.
训练非常短暂，仅有四个半日的课程
The training was a very simple,four half days of lessons.
然后你就得独自飞行。因为飞机是单座的
Then you had to do your first flight on your own because the machines were single-seaters.
我们必须保证不会弄坏飞机
We had to give our word that we would not damage the machines.
否则我们就会受到惩罚或者立即遣送回原岗位
otherwise we would be punished or immediately sent back to the units we came from.
这样的警告牢记在心中，
With that warning uppermost in their minds,
即便是有经验的飞行员，后续训练也被当成首飞来对待
even for these experienced pilots, the first flights were always *never again.
坐在机翼上的士官向我讲解飞机内部，特别是那些要密切注意的地方
The sergeant who was on the wing explained to me the interior of the plane, especially what to look out for.
例如引擎用的汽油必须缓慢加装
For example, the gas for the engine was only *stepped up very slowly,
否则引擎就会熄火
otherwise the engine would stall.
涡轮引擎必须缓慢提速
The turbine engine had to get used to the speed very slowly,
所以必须非常小心
So one had to be very careful.
一旦起飞，Me-262将会超越飞行员的期望
Once in the air the experience of flying Me-262 surpassed all their expectations.
对任何狂热的飞行员来说，驾驶这架飞机都是最为非凡的体验
For any pilot passionate about flying. It was a most extraordinary experience,
特别是咆哮的引擎不在你身前
Especially so because the roaring engine was not in front of your nose.
所有噪音都在你身后
All the noise was behind you.
多好的飞机
It is a wonderful thing.
飞机的速度极快
The speed was really enormous.
飞行特性的优势极大
And the flying characteristics were so advantageous.
你坐在飞机里，顿生自信
You actually had a sense of confidence in that machine.
虽然德国飞行员对起飞和速度赞不绝口
Although the German pilots would praise the takeoff and speed at the plane,
但降落比较麻烦
It was the landing that gave them problems.
在He109上，飞行员可以关闭引擎缓慢滑行降落
In a 109 plane, one could just switch off the engine and drift done slowly.
但在262上绝无可能
But in this plane it wasn't possible at all.
我以400至500英里(643-804km/h)的时速飞行，而且无法减速
I was traveling at a speed of four hundred and five hundred miles per hour and couldn't reduce it.
这飞机就是不下降
The plane just wouldn't descend.
我看着高度计绕圈飞行，直到3000英尺(914m)时才请求降落
I looked at the altitude meter and had to fly in circles until I finally reached an altitude of three thousand feet then asked for permission to land,
我放下起落架，慢慢接近跑道
I lowered the landing gear and slowly approached the runway.
最终我安全降落，如释重负
Finally, I was able to land safely and was greatly relieved.
和往常降落不同，这次我汗流浃背
In contrast to my usual take off in landings, it was completely soaked with sweat.
最初计划是只有王牌飞行员才能驾驶Me-262
Initially, it was planned that only fighter aces would fly the plane,
但4年的战争让帝国空军精锐尽损
But four years of war had taken its toll on Luftwaffe's finest,
那些只有10小时飞行经验的普通飞行员也被征召入伍
So regular pilots, some with as little as ten hours' flying experience were drafted in.
对于新手来说，驾驶Me-262并不简单
But for inexperienced pilots, the Me-262 was not an easy plan to fly,
超过200名飞行员死于训练
And over two hundred pilots were killed in training alone.
显然，最初的那批人，包括我在内
of course, the first ones to whom I count myself as well.
我们是最好的飞行员
We were the best.
但那些后来者基本都是新手，无法操控这种飞机
But those who followed us were often at the beginning of their pilot training and didn't cope with the machine.
让他们来驾驶喷气机是完全不负责任的
To put those people in the jet was totally irresponsible.
我们损失惨重
We had huge losses there.
1944年中，那些在训练中存活下来的飞行员被送往一个新组建的中队
By mid 1944, those pilots that had survived the training was sent to a newly formed squadrons.
草率地组建成的地勤团队来维护这些精妙的武器
Ground crews too, were hastily recruited to service and maintain these new wonder weapons.
通常来说，地勤人员努力工作 确保飞机一直处于就绪状态
Generally speaking, my experience was that the ground crew tried very hard to ensure that the planes were always ready for takeoff.
我和他们不太熟悉，因为我经常要准备行动或是等待紧急任务
I did not get to know them well enough because I've always had to be ready for action and was waiting for an emergency takeoff.
但有时紧急情况根本就没有发生
Sometimes that was not happen at all.
所以说人的半生都在徒劳等待中度过
Hence the saying half of one's life *will waits in vain.
然而等待是短暂的
Yet the waiting was short lived,
随着数千架轰炸机重创德国，
With thousands of bombers now pounding Germany,
每名可用的飞行员都投入行动中
Every available pilots was thrown into action.
1944年7月25日
on July the 25th 1944,
一架Me-262成为首架用于实战的喷气战斗机，
它击落了一架飞过慕尼黑正在拍照的英国蚊式侦察机
An Me-262 became the first jet airplane to be used in combat when it shot down a British photo reconnaissance mosquito flying over Munich.
看来德国赢得了喷气战斗机的竞赛
It now appeared that the race for the jet fighter had been won
空战胜利的荣耀也弥漫在德国空军中
And with it the prize of victory in the skies, which was now within the Luftwaffe's *staff.
1944年夏末，更多的德军飞行员驾驶新Me-262参战
During the late summer of 1944, more and more German Luftwaffe pilots were taking their new Me-262 jet fighters into battle.
似乎德军终于找到了可以击败盟军轰炸机和高速护航战斗机的武器
It seemed as though finally they now had a weapon that could beat the Allied bombers and their high speed escorts.
两组四架野马组成紧密队形
There were two groups of four mustangs in close formation,
他们非常自信。但他们没有看见我，这是他们的失误
And they were so incredibly confident. they hadn't seen me, and that was a mistake.
我为那些没有注意我的人感到遗憾
I actually felt sorry for the guys is they hadn't noticed me.
我从右侧低处飞向那里。
I came from deep, low, right and flew in there.
飞机有4门30mm MK108机炮，火力极强
We had four thirty millimeter guns the MK108,that was an incredible fire,
长长的机翼目标都展现在我面前，不可能打偏
Because the whole thing presented itself to me was a long outstretched point. You couldn't actually miss.
之后就打下了两架战斗机
And then two fighters dropped down.
我看到其中一架飞行员跳伞，另一架则没有
With one I saw a parachute travel with the other one. I didn't.
情况就是这样
That was such a case.
1944年末，Me262对盟军轰炸机造成了毁灭性的打击
by late 1944 the 262s were attacking the Allied bombers with devastating effect,
盟军战斗机和轰炸机组不知道如何处理它们
Allied fighter and bomber crews were unsure how to deal with them.
它们的速度和火力都过于完美了
(飞行速度超过盟军轰炸机后置机枪炮台的转动速度[译者注])
Their speed and firepower were just too perfect.
我们一枪也打不中，然后它们就飞走了
We couldn't get a shot. And then he goes.
咻~ 再见了您呐~
Shh~ bye bye fellows~
我和地勤人员说：我刚才看到一个真正的飞行员
And I just said the *ground crew we just saw a real pilot.
我们头顶飞过一架Me-262，但只是瞥见了一眼
他从3点钟方向攻击并冲过机群
We were jumped by an Me-262 and only got a very short glimpse of him because he made an attack from about three o'clock high and he came down through the group.
他飞得太快，很难看清楚
He went by so fast, we couldn't hardly see him.
这着实令人震惊，因为从未见过这样的飞机
It was really shocked because it was like nothing that we'd seen before.
战争早期，德国飞行员还没有体会到自己拥有这样的空中霸权
The German pilots had not felt such supremacy in the air since the early days of the war.
不过他们坚信这种不可思议的飞机可以扭转局势
They felt sure that this incredible plane would turn the tide.
我在德累斯顿区域飞行，下降到16000英尺(4876.8米)
I flew to the area around Dresden and went down to 16,000 feet.
我看见两架战斗机在我上方
I spotted two fighter planes, as they were above me,
我拉升高度，将一架敌机纳入视野
I increased my altitude and I took one of the fighter planes in my sights.
当时，机枪和机炮都是自动开启的
In those days, the machine guns and cannons were automatically switched on.
四门机炮喷出一串火舌
I had four cannons and I gave off a burst of fire.
在我意识到命中之前，敌机飞行员就跳伞了
And before I knew it, the pilot parachuted out of his plane.
我甚至都不知道打中了哪里
Where I had hit him I did not know.
一切都是全新的，我就感觉到快
It was all very new, much too fast.
突然我看到了第二架敌机在我前方
And then suddenly I saw the second fighter plane in front of me.
我向他开火
And I fired at it,
他被旗帜一样的烟雾包围着坠落
and it went down, surrounded by smoke that looked like a flag.
但轰炸机才是Me-262真正的猎物
But it was the bombers that were the Me-262's real prey.
德军飞行员艾尔弗雷德在执行他的第13次任务
一次例行巡逻中碰见了B-17轰炸机
Luftwaffe pilot, Alfred Arms was on a routine patrol when he came across a B-17 on its 13th mission.
没有过多讨论，每个人就选定了目标
Everyone quickly chose a plane without having any great discussions about whether they were going to take this or the other plane.
替代讨论的办法是：说明自己最佳的进攻位置
Instead, you would say the best position for me is the one in the middle.
空中有很多敌机，因此很容易就能选择一个目标
There were enough planes in the sky, which made it easy to pick one.
在那架B-17上的后射手正是19岁的克雷格
The rear gunner in that particular B-17 was nineteen year old Craig Bennett.
他太快了
He came so fast.
给你的时间只够扣动扳机，立马开火
all you had time was just pull the triggers and let the guns fire.
我瞄准了突然出现在前方的B-17（绰号：“飞行堡垒”）
I was aiming at a fortress when suddenly ahead of me,
中队队长被卷入巨大的火墙中，其他人也消失了
There was a large wall of fire into which the captain of my squadron and others disappeared.
第一架飞机是领队，他袭击了我们的飞机
The first plane was the leader and he hit our plane.
飞机就这样爆炸了
The plane just blew up.
他的飞机和我们的飞机一起爆炸了
The whole plane exploded, his plane and ours.
我得以从火墙上飞过
I was able to fly over the wall of fire.
原来，B-17爆炸会让附近范围都处在火焰中
It turned out that the fortress had exploded and taken to adjacent flames with that.
这就是B-17爆炸的威力
That's how big the explosion was.
机尾开始碎裂
And the tail broke off.
飞机开始坠落
and started falling.
其余的机体都消失了
And the rest of the plane was gone.
我是唯一幸存下来的
I was the only one they'd got my *.
克雷格在接下来的战争期间成为俘虏
Craig Bennett was to spend the rest of the war as a POW.
但这并不是一边倒的战斗
Yet it was not all a one-sided fight.
对这些神奇武器感到震惊的同时,
Once they got over the shock of these new wonder weapons,
盟军飞行员开始逐渐掌握对付德军喷气机的办法
the Allied pilots slowly began to learn how to deal with the German jet.
首要的问题就是如何克服速度上的巨大劣势
The first problem was how to overcome the huge speed disadvantage.
飞行员发现当野马战斗机进入垂直俯冲状态，
The pilot's found that when they put the Mustang into a steep dive,
他们就能和Me-262有相同的速度
their speed was the same as the Me-262.
因此我把油门推到底
So I just bent the throttle as far as it could forward,
一刻不停
Without going through the stop.
接下来
And,
因为他在做一点转向，所以能非常缓慢地接近他
Slowly, very, very slowly start gaining along the guy because he was making a little turn.
每当他转向一点，我就能逐渐接近
And each time you turn a little bit, I get a little closer.
这家伙是个新手
this guy was inexperienced.
我很确信，因为他看见第一架敌机时既没有飞过去也没有出手攻击
*I'm sure because when he saw the first tracers,either *go by him or hit his airplane.
而是开始转向
He made a turn.
如果他把机头朝下，我们怎么才能逃走呢
If you to put his nose down, how do we run?
我们可能就被击落了
We probably never got.
这是一段敌机进入我方射程的影片
A movie where we got in range.
盟军飞行员也发现Me-262的机动能力不如螺旋桨飞机
The Allied pilots also found that the Me-262 did not respond as quick in a turn as propeller planes.
这个影响是致命的
This would have deadly consequences.
我位于他转向圈的内侧时，就可以像打靶一样射击它的头部
I was on the inside of his circle and I was able to get a bead on him and shoot in front of him,
这样他就会自己撞上子弹
so he would fly into the bullets.
但Me-262最脆弱的还是起飞和降落的时候
But it was on takeoff and landing at the Me-262, with at its most vulnerable.
盟军飞行员埋伏在机场附近
Allied pilots lay in wait around the airfields.
上百名Me-262飞行员死于这种袭击方式
Hundreds of 262 pilots were to dine In this way.
美国人改变策略，专注于驻扎喷气机的机场
The Americans change their tactics to concentrate on all airfields, where jet fighter units were stationed.
这样他们就能在我们最脆弱的时候发动袭击
This way they were able to hit us when we were most vulnerable.
——起飞和降落的时候
During startup and landing.
在起飞的时候，我们速度不足
During takeoff, we did not have enough speed.
降落时，我们需要减速
And when landing, we had to reduce it.
这就是问题所在
That was the problem.
随着战争天平向盟军倾斜
With the tide of war turning against them,
Me-262的空中优势荡然无存
the Me-262 superiority in the skies was over.
更多的飞机被击落，恐惧一直萦绕在飞行员心头
More and more planes were being shot down and fear was ever-present in the remaining pilots minds.
战争后期，飞行员才发现
The thoughts would only enter your head at a later stage when within the squadron,
中队里三分之一至四分之一的队员，每周就更换一批
nearly every third or fourth person had to be replaced every week.
战争持续越久，这种情况就越多
The longer the war lasted, the more this occurred.
我认为这导致了战争的结束
I believe this led to the end of the war.
愤怒于德军高层糟蹋喷气中队的行为
Furious that the new jet squadrons were being wasted by the German High Command,
在加兰德将军和其他著名王牌飞行员的坚持下
and under insistence of General Galland and other famous aces,
元首勉强同意将1/20的Me-262改为战斗机型号
Hitler reluctantly allowed every twentieth Me-262 to be built as a fighter.
这种做法完全错误
It was a completely wrong thing to do.
有些轰炸机被当作夜间战斗机使用
And some of the bombers were used as night fighters.
他们完全误判了局势
“they had totally misjudge the situation.
我只能假设他们执着于自己的错觉
I can only assume that they were following their own delusion.
领导人的命令在1944年末终于被撤销
The order of the leader was at last rescinded in late 1944.
元首终于下令所有Me-262都作为战斗机型号生产
Hitler finally ordered that all Me-262s should now be built as fighters.
随着盟军进军德国本土，Me262战斗机似乎来得太晚也太少了
With the allies marching into Germany, was it too little and too late?
1945年初，几乎所有Me-262工厂被盟军摧毁
By early 1945, and with nearly all her factories destroyed by the Allies,
德国人发现几乎无法生产急需的喷气战斗机
Germany was finding it almost impossible to produce the jet fighters so desperately needed.
因此提出了一个新办法
So a novel solution was brought about.
轰炸确实减缓了生产
The bombing did slow everything down.
但如果我们有足够的材料，就能生产出所需数量的战机
But if we had enough material, we could have manufactured the required numbers.
比如说43或44架
let's say 43 or 44.
最后我们都习惯了
In the end, we got used to it.
更多人进入森林
more went into the woods,
我们在那搭起大型掩体和伪装帐篷
where we put up large shelters, camouflage tents.
工厂遍及德国各地，Me-262的零件在夜色掩护下通过卡车、马车
Manufacturer throughout Germany, Sections of the Me-262 were then delivered under cover of darkness by truck, horse and cart,
甚至是自行车运输，然后再森林中组装起来
and even bicycles to be fully assembled in forests.
超过800架是通过这种方式组装起来的
Over eight hundred were to be built in this way.
当越来越多的Me-262被盟军战斗机击落，
But as more and more Me-262 were being destroyed by allied fighters,
德国空军的精英也越来越少
so too with the cream of the German Luftwaffe.
有一天，一架飞机和我飞机上方碰撞，我的飞机起火了
One day a plane came crashing down above me and my plane caught fire.
我只能跳伞
I had to bail out.
这次我只能用降落伞落地了
That's how I had to land with my parachute.
对我来说，战争结束了
And that was the end of the war for me.
突然一声巨响
There was suddenly a big bang.
短暂停顿后，我没有像往常那样回头看
For a couple of brief moments, I did not look back as I would usually do.
而是望向天空，看看发生了什么
I was looking in the sky to see what had happened.
某处发出一阵闪光
There was a flash somewhere.
之后我就发现引擎起火
And then I saw the engine was catching fire.
那时，我位于云层上空4000英尺(1219.2米)
At that stage, I was about four thousand feet above the layer of cloud.
一看到起火，我立即俯冲进云层
Upon seeing the fire, I immediately dived into the clouds,
我改变航向，向左飞行以避开火焰
I changed course and turned left in order to get out of the line of fire.
我想跳伞逃生
I wanted to jump up with a parachute.
接着我想起有人和我说，如果你十分恐惧，想要跳伞
Then I remembered that someone had once told me that if you are too frightened to jump off,
把控制杆推向一边
then push the joystick to the side,
用脚支撑自己，然后把自己推出去
Stand on it with your foot and push yourself off.
这就是我做的事
That's what I did.
战争快结束的时候
Towards the end of the war,
根本没有足够受过训练的飞行员来驾驶喷气战斗机
There simply were not enough trained pilots to fly the jet fighter.
现有的Me-262生产也停滞不前
Even if there had been the production of the Me-262, had ground to a halt,
他们无法生产足够的喷气战斗机来阻止潮水般涌入的盟军
They simply could not build enough jet fighters to stem the tide of the conquering allies.
德国最终在1945年5月7日投降
Germany finally surrendered on May, the 7th 1945.
当城市和工厂都被摧毁
As cities and factories were totally smashed,
同样，喷气战斗机工业也被破坏了
So too, with the jet aircraft industry.
接下来的几个月里
In the following months,
英美苏为这架分散在德国各处的神奇飞机的遗产争执不休
Britain, America and Russia squabbled over the carcasses of the wonder jets that were scattered throughout Germany
对飞机进行彻底研究之后，他们都开始建立自己的喷气机工业
and picking through the bones, they began to build their own jet aircraft industries.
在一个叫Lusty(德国空军技术)的行动中
In an operation called operation Lusty
(LUftwaffe Secret TechnologY[译者注])
通过沃森上校的命令
Under the command of colonel Watson,
美国人收集了所有他们能找到的德国飞机
the Americans gathered all the German planes they could find.
它们被空运到法国瑟堡，之后被船运回美国进行评估
They were flown to Cherbourg in France and then shipped to America for revaluation.
沃森的团队由一群美国飞行员组成，
他们负责夺取德国飞行器并送往法国海岸，
最终送回美国做进一步分析
Watson's *wizards were a group of American pilots tasked with capturing flying German aircraft to the French coast and bringing them back to the United States for testing and evaluation,
他们有义务将这个最新技术带回美国，因此要和英国苏联竞争
The commitment to getting this new technology back to the United States, and they were actually racing against the British and the Soviets.
这样做可以确保美国在战后的航空优势
To do this would ensure that America would have an aeronautical superiority in the postwar period,
美国人对Me-262做了大量的测试
The Americans began an extensive testing program of the Me-262.
通过对这架德国战斗机喷气引擎和气动设计的分析，
By analyzing the jet turbines and wind design at this German fighter,
美国人就可以生产自己设计的机型了
They were able to produce their own design,
这就是后来性能极佳的F-86佩刀战斗机
which was to become the fabulous F-86 Sabre.
直到通过lusty行动和其他项目获取德国喷气技术后，
It's not until the German jet technology that's brought over through operation lusty and other programs
北美航空公司才开发出F-86战斗机，
尤其是它的后掠翼设计有德国技术的影子
that aircraft like North American F-86 with its swept-wing especially reflect the German technology.
这也让美国学到了设计合适且高效的喷气机的方式
And the way to design a proper and efficient jet airplane.
苏联也发现了Me-262的秘密
The Russians also dealt into the Me-262 secrets,
在英国喷气技术的帮助下，设计出了米格15
And with the help of British jet technology would later build then MIG-15.
事实上，苏联工业的飞跃靠的是二战末期从德国人那里拿来的技术
Really, the boost for the Russian engineering industry was what they captured from the Germans at the end of the Second World War.
苏联航空工业的发展关键是得到了我们的最新引擎
The main thing, though, really for the Russian aircraft industry was when we gave them our latest engine
这让米格15从设计还不错的飞机一跃成为世界级飞机
and that allowed to MIG-15 to go from being an average aircraft with good design to a world beater.
和Me-262一起到美国的还有它的设计者奥海恩
Along with the Me-262’s moved to America when designer Hans von Ohain,
他后来成为美国空军航空推进技术的首席科学家
he was to become the chief scientist of aero Propulsion for the United States Air Force.
弗兰克·惠特尔最后也来到了美国
Frank Whittle eventually moved to America,
他成为了几个航空项目的顾问
where he became a consultant on several aviation projects.
威利·梅塞施密特
Wilhelm Messerschmitt
Me-262之父，留在德国帮助重建支离破碎的航空工业
The father of the Me-262 remained in Germany and helps in rebuilding their shattered aircraft industry.
大量的盟军飞机成为了Me-262的受害者
Hundreds of Allied aircraft were to fall victim to the Me-262.
但是代价也非常沉重
But at a terrible price,
生产的1400架Me-262中，没有几架能在战争中幸存
hardly any of the 1400 Me-262s that were built survived the war.
仍然有很多人相信，如果Me-262再早点服役
Yet many people still believe that if the Me-262 had entered service earlier,
它或许能使德国免于战败
it could have save Germany from defeat.
有很多假设，例如提早半年引进这项计划
There has been a lot of speculation and perhaps if they could have introduced the whole program half a year earlier.
但话说回来，这会被用于战争吗?只有天知道
But if you are truthfully, would it have decided to war? Only the gods know.
德国在让喷气机升空方面获得了胜利
Germany had won the race to get a jet fighter into the air.
它超越了一切对手
It outclassed all its rivals,
在它几个月短暂的服役期中
And in its short operational life of seven months,
Me-262将空战的领域推向了一个全新的高度
the Me-262 had pushed forward the frontiers of air combat to new heights.
那段时间里，Me-262就是世界上最好的战斗机
At the time it was the best fighter plane in the world.
作为一架飞机来说，它是一个杰作
And as an aircraft, It was an exceptional solution.
我们惊喜地发现 没有飞机可以比Me-262做的更好
We were surprised that the others could not do better.
毫无疑问，就算不能称为世界航空史的著名飞机，
Me-262也算的上是德国航空史上最著名的飞机之一
The Me-262 was undoubtedly one of the most famous airplanes in the whole history of German aviation, If not the world.
生而为骇人的毁灭者
Born out of a need to be a fearsome destroyer
从首飞那天起，
From the day at first flew,
它宣告螺旋桨飞机的终结，预示着喷气新纪元的黎明
It spelled the end of propeller driven aircraft and heralded the dawning of the new jet age.